Speaker: Part 3
Some months later, Mrs. Myers appeared in court.
"So, Mrs. Myers," said the judge, "what’s all this with the cards?"
"I need to earn money," said the old lady.
"At my age, I’m not going to be a dancer!"
"Somebody complained that you are not reading the cards properly," said the judge.
"If they’re going to pay you a pound, people expect a proper reading."
"But most people don’t complain," the old lady replied.
"I tell them things they want to hear. And sometimes I even get it right…"
"But," said the judge, "here we have a witness.
Please tell us about it, Mrs. McCleary."
"Mrs. Myers read the cards for me," said Mrs. McCleary.
"She told me that in a year I’d be married,
that my husband would be a rich young man,
and that we’d move abroad."
"But Mrs. McCleary is already married," said the judge.
"She married Inspector McCleary three years ago.
So how do you explain this nonsense, Mrs. Myers?"
"Well, she said she was single," said the old lady, calmly.
"So I predicted a wedding for her and a rich husband."
"And what about the old man and the journey abroad?" asked Mrs. McCleary.
"For something more to say," replied Mrs. Myers.
"For a pound, you need to say more than just two things."
"You are a fraud, Mrs. Myers," said the judge.
"You must pay a fine of fifty pounds.
I hope you learn your lesson.”